Guide to the Othniel Charles Marsh Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Othniel Charles Marsh papers
1817-1899
MS 343
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
30.75
(59 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, diaries, notebooks, school notes, and other papers of O.C. Marsh, scientist and first professor of paleontology at Yale and in the United States. Of special interest is the rather extensive correspondence Marsh carried on with many prominent scientists of his time; included are letters from Charles Darwin, Leonard and Thomas Huxley, Simon Newcomb, and Benjamin Silliman Sr. and Jr. Also included are materials relating to Marsh's education at Andover, Yale, and in Germany, family papers, and papers reflecting his involvement with the Cardiff Giant hoax and the Red Cloud controversy.
Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of O.C. Marsh, 1899, and of the Archives of the Peabody Museum, Yale University.
Custodial History
From 1940-1970 the Marsh Papers were divided between the Peabody Museum of Natural History at Yale and the Yale University Library.
Existence and Location of Copies
The entire collection (excluding boxes 21, 43A, 43B, 49A, 55, folio items, and Accession 2010-M-050) is also available on microfilm (29 reels, 35mm.) from Scholarly Resources, Inc., Wilmington, Delaware.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The collection is available on microfilm excluding boxes 21, 43A, 43B, 49A, 55, folio items, and Accession 2010-M-050. Except for these boxes, patrons must use FILM HM38 instead of the originals.
Biographical / Historical
Othniel Charles Marsh, born in Lockport, New York, in 1831, was the son of Caleb and Mary Peabody Marsh. When he was three years old his mother died of cholera, and thereafter her bachelor brother, George Peabody, assumed full financial responsibility for Othniel's education at Andover, Yale (class of 1860), and in Germany. When he returned to Yale in 1865, Marsh was appointed the first professor of paleontology in the western hemisphere and influenced his uncle, George Peabody, to provide funds for the construction of a Natural History Museum at Yale. While searching for fossils in the western states, Marsh's discoveries included an extinct bird with teeth and eighty new forms of dinosaurs. These won him acclaim at home and in Europe. Owing to the death at mid-term of the president of the National Academy of Science, Marsh became acting president from 1880-1883. He was then elected president for two successive six-year terms, filling that office for longer than any previous or subsequent incumbent. Marsh devoted so much of his inherited fortune to the collecting of specimens for Yale that at the end of his life he found himself forced to mortgage his Prospect Street home in New Haven. Never having married, he named Yale his sole beneficiary, but his estate amounted to very little, except for the $18,694 realized when the contents of his home were auctioned in New York. Marsh died in his New Haven home from pneumonia on March 18, 1899.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, diaries, notebooks, school notes, and other papers of O.C. Marsh, scientist and first professor of paleontology at Yale and in the United States. Of special interest is the rather extensive correspondence Marsh carried on with many prominent scientists of his time; included are letters from Charles Darwin, Leonard and Thomas Huxley, Simon Newcomb, and Benjamin Silliman Sr. and Jr. Also included are materials relating to Marsh's education at Andover, Yale, and in Germany, family papers, and papers reflecting his involvement with the Cardiff Giant hoax and the Red Cloud controversy.
Arrangement
Arranged in seven series and one addition: I. Correspondence. II. Marsh Family. III. Education of O. C. Marsh. IV. Writings of O. C. Marsh. V. Biographical Information. VI. Cardiff Giant Hoax. VII. Red Cloud Agency.
Cardiff giant; Indians of North America -- Government relations; Science; Europe; Diaries; Paleontologists; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910; Barnard, Frederick A. P. (Frederick Augustus Porter), 1809-1889; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Beecher, Charles Emerson, 1856-1904; Bell, Alexander Graham, 1847-1922; Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902; Billings, John S. (John Shaw), 1838-1913; Boss, Lewis, 1846-1912; Bradley, Frank Howe, 1838-1879; Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910; Brush, George Jarvis, 1831-1912; Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917; Carter, Franklin, 1837-1919; Clarke, Frank Wigglesworth, 1847-1931; Coffin, J. H. C. (John Huntington Crane), 1815-1890; Condon, Thomas, 1822-1907; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882; Davidson, Thomas, 1817-1885; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Emmons, Samuel Franklin, 1841-1911; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899; Gaudry, Albert, 1827-1908; Geinitz, Hanns Bruno, 1814-1900; Gibbs, Wolcott, 1822-1908; Gilbert, Grove Karl, 1843-1918; Gilman, Daniel C. (Daniel Coit), 1831-1908; Goode, G. Brown (George Brown), 1851-1896; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888; Grinnell, George Bird, 1849-1938; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884; Hague, A. (Arnold), 1840-1917; Hall, Asaph, III, 1829-1907; Hall, James, 1811-1898; Hartt, Charles Frederick, 1840-1878; Hatcher, J. B. (John Bell), 1861-1904; Hawley, Joseph R. (Joseph Roswell), 1826-1905; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878; Hilgard, J. E. (Julius Erasmus), 1825-1891; Howell, Edwin E. (Edwin Eugene), 1845-1911; Hulke, J. W. (John Whitaker), 1830-1895; Huxley, Leonard, 1860-1933; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895; King, Clarence, 1842-1901; Lakes, Arthur, 1844-1917; Langley, S. P. (Samuel Pierpont), 1834-1906; Lucas, Frederic A. (Frederic Augustus), 1852-1929; Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899; Meek, F. B. (Fielding Bradford), 1817-1876; Meigs, Montgomery C. (Montgomery Cunningham), 1816-1892; Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1822-1908; Mudge, B. F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1817-1879; Newberry, J. S. (John Strong), 1822-1892; Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905; Pickering, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1846-1919; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895; Poulton, Edward Bagnall, Sir, 1856-1943; Powell, John Wesley, 1834-1902; Remsen, Ira, 1846-1927; Rogers, William Barton, 1804-1882; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903; Sternberg, Charles H. (Charles Hazelius), 1850-; Stevenson, James, 1840-1888; Sutter, John Augustus, 1826-1897; Walcott, Charles D. (Charles Doolittle), 1850-1927; Ward, Henry A. (Henry Augustus), 1834-1906; White, Charles A. (Charles Abiathar), 1826-1910; Whitney, Eli, 1847-1924; Williston, Samuel Wendell, 1851-1918; Woodward, Henry, 1832-1921; Marsh family; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs. Pine Ridge Agency; Geological Survey (U.S.) -- History; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.); Peabody Museum of Natural History; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- General correspondence, 1814-1903; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The general correspondence, previously housed at the Peabody Museum, is predominantly scientific in nature. There are more than twelve thousand items, beginning with letters written to and from Marsh following his return from Germany in 1865 and continuing until his death in 1899. Among the socially and scientifically prominent correspondents represented are Cleveland Abbe; Alexander and Louis Agassiz; Spencer Baird; Phineas Barnum; Albert Bierstadt; George Jarvis Brush; William Fredrick Cody; James Dwight Dana; Charles Darwin; Ulysses S. Grant; Asa Gray; Joseph Henry; Ferdinand Hayden; Leonard and Thomas Huxley; Simon Newcomb; Benjamin Silliman, Sr. and Jr.; Herbert Spencer; and Eli Whitney. Relatively few of Marsh's own letters have survived, except for occasional rough drafts that he retained. After the advent of the typewriter, however, his side of the correspondence is represented more frequently.
  The most voluminous correspondence is with his co-workers and "bonediggers" such as C. E. and M. P. Felch, George Bird Grinnell, John B. Hatcher, Arthur Lakes, Benjamin F. Mudge, Samuel W. Williston, and W. H. Reed. When each specimen was received in New Haven, it was assigned an identifying number, which was also inscribed within a parallelogram on the accompanying letter or letters.
  Marsh's fossil collecting reached its peak in the 1870s and 1880s. His autocratic disposition led to difficulties with some of his colleagues. His lifelong rivalry with Edward C. Cope, who was his junior by nine years and who also aspired to the presidency of the National Academy of Science but was never elected, was a discredit to both men. Their quarrel is sparsely documented in the correspondence, except for an exchange of letters in 1873. There is also an excerpt from a letter written in December of the same year by one of Marsh's loyal diggers, announcing that Cope had inspected Marsh territory and that Davendorf "... discovered marks distinclty made, I presume, by Cope, so I judged he could strike certain places next spring. These marks are now defaced by the sole of my boot, but I know where they are."
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent.
  General
  Due to a numbering error, there are gaps in the the folder number sequence. Box 5, folder 201 and Box 6, folder 252 do not exist.
  - Abbe, Cleveland (1838-1916), 1884-1893; cuid0 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbot, Henry Larcom (1831-1927), 1882-1894; cuid1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aberdeen, John Campbell Gordon (1847-1934), 1894-1895; cuid2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Andrew Leith (?-1882), 1878; cuid3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Charles Francis (1835-1915), 1889; cuid4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adam, Henry (1838-1918), 1879; cuid5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Henry Martyn (1844-1909), 1880; cuid6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adam, John M., 1870-1874; cuid7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adams, L.S., 1877; cuid8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agassiz, Alexander (1835-1910), 1876-1886; cuid9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agassiz, Louis (1807-1873), 1862-1873; cuid10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alaska Commercial Company, 1872; cuid11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alexander, W.M., 1891; cuid12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Allen, A.H., 1876; cuid13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Allen, Harrison (1841-1897), 1870-1874; cuid14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Allen, Joel Asaph (1838-1921), 1867-1876; cuid15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Allen, O.P., 1869; cuid16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allison, William Boyd (1829-1908), 1892; cuid17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alvord, Benjamin (1813-1884), 1868-1871; cuid18 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ameglino, Florentino (1854-1911), 1893; cuid19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ami, Henry Marc (1858-?), 1898; cuid20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Anderson, A., 1870-1871; cuid21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Anderson, Joseph (1826, 1916), 1869; cuid22 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Andrews, Ebenezer Ealdwin (1821-1880), 1867; cuid23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Andrews, Edmund (1824-1904), 1868; cuid24 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Andrews, Joseph Ryde (?-1906), 1902; cuid25 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Andrews, S.W.F., 1879; cuid26 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Arkell, Tufts and Co., 1874; cuid27 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Arnold, L.C., 1892; cuid28 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Arnold, Mat thew, 1883; cuid29 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Arthur, Chester Alan (1830-1886), 1883; cuid30 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ashley, E.G., 1880-1883; cuid31 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Astor, C. Augusta, 1886; cuid32 (Box 1, Folder 33A)
  - Astor, J.J. and Mrs., undated; cuid33 (Box 1, Folder 33B)
  - Augun, Christopher Colmbus (1821-1898), 1871; cuid34 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Auld, Robert C., 1881-1891; cuid35 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Avery, John, 1869; cuid36 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bache, R. Meade, 1889; cuid37 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bagg, R.M., 1898; cuid38 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton (1823-1888), 1868-1871; cuid39 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton (1823-1888), 1872-1873; cuid40 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton (1823-1888), 1874-1878; cuid41 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton (1823-1888), 1879-1887; cuid42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard (1870-1946), 1898; cuid43 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Baker, William A., 1874; cuid44 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Baldwin, Charles, 1880; cuid45 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Baldwin, David, 1876; cuid46 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Baldwin, David, 1877-1878; cuid47 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Baldwin, David, 1878-1881; cuid48 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Baniard, Charles, 1888; cuid49 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - A.L. Bancroft and Co., 1871; cuid50 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Bankhead, Henry Cary, 1870; cuid51 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Barbour, E.H., 1882-1888; cuid52 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Barbour, R.C., 1884; cuid53 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Barfoot, Joseph L., 1872-1875; cuid54 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Baring, Cecil, 1894; cuid55 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Barker, Fordyce, 1889; cuid56 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Barker, George Frederick (1835-1910), 1868-1885; cuid57 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Barker, George Frederick (1835-1910), 1886-1897; cuid58 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Barker, T. G., 1869; cuid59 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter (1809-1889), 1879-1887; cuid60 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Barnhart, G.W., 1868?; cuid61 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Barnum, Phineas Taylor (1810-1891), 1880-1886; cuid62 (Box 2, Folder 61A)
  - Barrett, John E., 1874; cuid63 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Earrett, S.J., 1875-1881; cuid64 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Barrett, W.E., 1869-1879; cuid65 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Barringer, Victor C., 1888-1890; cuid66 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Barrois, Charles (1851-1939), 1896-1897; cuid67 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Barton, George L., 1877; cuid68 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Barus, Carl, 1894-1895; cuid69 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Baskett, J.N., 1894; cuid70 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Basor, George W., 1870; cuid71 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Bates, James M., 1887; cuid72 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Bath, Nick, 1886; cuid73 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Baur, George, 1884-1886; cuid74 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Baur, George, 1887-1890; cuid75 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Bayard, Thomas Francis (1828-1898), 1886; cuid76 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Bayet, Ernest, undated; cuid77 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Beach, D.N., 1881; cuid78 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Beadle, E.R., 1867-1871; cuid79 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Beadle, Herbert H., 1869-1886; cuid80 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Beck, William, 1884-1885; cuid81 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Beck, William, 1885-1886; cuid82 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Beck, William, 1886-1887; cuid83 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Becker, Frank L., 1886; cuid84 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Becker, G.F., 1882; cuid85 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Beckexs, Samuel, 1888; cuid86 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Beckwith, H.C., 1877-1879; cuid87 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Beckwith, Leonard, 1874; cuid88 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Bedell, C.A., 1874; cuid89 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Beecher, Charles Emerson (1856-1904), 1887-1897; cuid90 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Beecher, William C., 1871-1873; cuid91 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Belcher, J.H., 1885; cuid92 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Bell, Alexander Graham (1847-1922), 1883-1889; cuid93 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Bell, Jesse, 1877-1878; cuid94 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Bell, John, 1884; cuid95 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Bell, Robert M., 1889-1893; cuid96 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Belt, Thomas (1832-1878), 1875; cuid97 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Bend, C.H., 1889; cuid98 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Benecke, E.W., 1879; cuid99 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Benedick, H.E., 1895-1896; cuid100 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Benjamin and Ford, 1891; cuid101 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Bennett, R.N., 1869; cuid102 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Berzelius, Jons Jakob, 1835; cuid103 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Berends, D.H., 1872-1874; cuid104 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Berger, Charles F., 1875-1885; cuid105 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Berlin, A. F., 1878; cuid106 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Berthoud, Edward L., 1861-1884; cuid107 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Bibbins, Arthur, 1894; cuid108 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Bien, Julius (1826-1909), 1870; cuid109 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Bierstadt, Albert (1830-1902), 1877-1888; cuid110 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Biggs, W.H., 1890; cuid111 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Bigot, A., 1897-1898; cuid112 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Billings, E., 1869; cuid113 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Billings, John Shand (1839-1913), 1885-1895; cuid114 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Binkley, S.H., 1868-1874; cuid115 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Blake, Clarence John (1843-1919), 1877; cuid116 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Blake, Henry Arthur, 1887; cuid117 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Blake, John M., 1894; cuid118 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Blake, William Phipps (1826-?), 1869-1886; cuid119 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Theodore Bliss and Company, 1868; cuid120 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Blunt, W. T., Jr., 1883; cuid121 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Boardman, William J., 1871; cuid122 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Boas, Franz (1858-?), 1884; cuid123 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Bonaparte, J.T., undated; cuid124 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Bonaparte, Roland Napoleon, 1893; cuid125 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Booth, W. F., 1895; cuid126 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Borcherdt, R, 1871-1874; cuid127 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Boschis, C., 1890; cuid128 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Boss, Lewis (1846-1912), 1891-1893; cuid129 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Bostwick, Thomas A., 1872-1896; cuid130 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Bostwick, Thomas A., 1898-1899; cuid131 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Bouly, M., 1895; cuid132 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Boutelle, C.O., 1889; cuid133 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Bowen, Edward S., 1873; cuid134 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Bowers, Lloyd W., 1898-1899; cuid135 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Bowers, William H., 1894; cuid136 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Bowman, John B., 1870; cuid137 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Boyd, H.W., 1873-1874; cuid138 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Boyd, H.W., 1875; cuid139 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Boyd, H.W., 1877-1878; cuid140 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Boynton, N.M., 1874; cuid141 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Brackett, S.G. 1881, cuid142 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Bradley, Frank Howe (1838-1879), 1867-1875; cuid143 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Brady, John Green (1848-1918), 1874; cuid144 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Branner, John Casper (1850-1922), 1893; cuid145 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Bratman, James C., 1867; cuid146 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Brendel, Dr., 1865; cuid147 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Brewer, A.L., 1871; cuid148 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Brewer, William Henry (1828-1910), 1874-1889; cuid149 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Brewster, C.G., 1868; cuid150 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Brian, H.T., 1883-1895; cuid151 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Brigham, S.H., 1894; cuid152 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Bristol, Eugene (letter of 1870 June 18 added 7/2/73), cuid153 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Letter of 1870 June 18 added 7/2/73.
  - Bromley, Isaac H., 1876; cuid154 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Brooks, Noah, 1881; cuid155 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Brooks, O.N., 1875; cuid156 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Brooks, W. K., 1887-1889; cuid157 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Broom, Allan D., 1885; cuid158 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Brous, H.A., 1876; cuid159 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1877-1883; cuid160 (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1883 July - 1884 January; cuid161 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1884 February - December; cuid162 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1885 January - June; cuid163 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1885 July - 1886 March; cuid164 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1886 May - December; cuid165 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1887 January - May; cuid166 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1887 June - September; cuid167 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1887 October - 1888 June; cuid168 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1888 July - 1889 June; cuid169 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Brown, Henry Armitt, 1868; cuid170 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Brown, James Stanley (1863-1939), 1883; cuid171 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Brown, James Temple, 1879; cuid172 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Brown, S.C., 1899; cuid173 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Brown, S.G., 1869-1870; cuid174 (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Brown, Sevellon A., 1879; cuid175 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Brucciani, D., 1875; cuid176 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Brumby, Professor R.T., 1869; cuid177 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Brush, George Jarvis (1831-1912), 1864-1895; cuid178 (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Buck, Dr. Francis D., 1895; cuid179 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Buckingharn, William W., 1862; cuid180 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Bucklin, S.S., 1880; cuid181 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Bull, Richard, 1885; cuid182 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Bumstead, Nathaniel Willis (1834-1912), 1870; cuid183 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Bunnell and Scranton, 1873; cuid184 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Bunsen, Georg von, 1893; cuid185 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Bunsen, Theodore von, 1872-1883; cuid186 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Burns, J.S., 1869; cuid187 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Burr, C.S., 1871; cuid188 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Burt, Andrew Sheridan (1839-1915), 1873-1887; cuid189 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Burwell, W.H., 1890; cuid190 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Bush, Lucy P., 1896; cuid191 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Bushnell, C., 1868; cuid192 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Butler, E., 1871; cuid193 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Butler, Robert, 1897; cuid194 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Butters, Alexander, 1877; cuid195 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Buxton, George, 1888; cuid196 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Byers, William N., 1875; cuid197 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Byrnes, R.M., 1871; cuid198 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Cabell, J.L., 1879; cuid199 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Cady, J. Cleaveland, 1874-1889; cuid200 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Caltin, 1891; cuid201 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Campbell, Quintin, 1871; cuid202 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Canfield, S.H., 1868; cuid203 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Cannon, George L., Jr., 1886-1897; cuid204 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Capellini, J., 1888-1899; cuid205 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Capen, Francis L., 1886; cuid206 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Caple, Sherman, 1886; cuid207 (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - Caplinger, Kate M. (Miss), 1898-1899; cuid208 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Carey, Elliott, 1878; cuid209 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Carlin, William E., 1877-1879; cuid210 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Carnegie, Andrew (1835-1919), 1890; cuid211 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Carpenter, Frank R., 1887; cuid212 (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Carpenter, J.H., 1878; cuid213 (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Carpenter, S.C., 1873; cuid214 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Carpenter, William Benjamin (1813-1885), 1882-1884; cuid215 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Carpenter, William Lewis, 1875-1899; cuid216 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Carr, Eugene Asa (1830-1910), 1870; cuid217 (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Carson, A.J.R., 1889; cuid218 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Carson, Luella C., 1892; cuid219 (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - Carter, Alexander, 1869; cuid220 (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Carter, Franklin (1837-?), 1866-1867; cuid221 (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - Carter, James Van A., 1872-1874; cuid222 (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Carter, James Van A., 1875-1876; cuid223 (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Carter, James Van A., 1877-1878; cuid224 (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Carter, William A, 1870-1872; cuid225 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Cary, S.H., 1868; cuid226 (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Case, Meigs, 1868-1871; cuid227 (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Case, Theodore S., 1878; cuid228 (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Casey, Lincoln, 1891; cuid229 (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Cassino, S, E, and Co., 1884; cuid230 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Catlin, R., 1895; cuid231 (Box 6, Folder 230A)
  - Cattell, J. McK., 1894; cuid232 (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Chamberlain, L. T., 1872; cuid233 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Chamberlain, T.C., 1883; cuid234 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Charnereau, Auguste, 1896; cuid235 (Box 6, Folder 234)